

EMC Corporation Global Residency Practice

PROFILE:

Over 6 years of experience in SAN/Storage. Expertise in administration, trouble shooting and configuration of V3, VMAX, DMX-4, DMX-3,VNX, Clarion CX3/CX4/IBM SVC, Hitachi, Open stack, AWS. Implemented several Storage Area Networks with Cisco and Brocade departmental switches. A strong understanding of computer systems and peripherals with good troubleshooting skills in the hardware and software area. Worked extensively on EMC disk storage arraysand sound knowledge in EMC Arrays. Knowledge to architect, maintain and implement SAN multi-platform environment including experience with Sun Solaris, HP-UX, IBM and Windows Operating Systems.

SKILLS:

Storage Arrays EMC V3, VMAX &DMX Family EMC VNX,VPLEX,RCP, EMC CLARiiON CX3/CX4, XtremIO, IBM SVC, HITACHI Arrays.

Storage Software's:

EMC Control Center (ECC) ProSphere, SMC, SPA and Solutions Enabler EMC Navisphere&Unishphere Recoverpoint. OpenStack.

SAN Fabrics:

CISCO Switches MDS 9513/9509 etc Brocade Switches 48K/12k/4900 **Operating Systems**. WINDOWS, Solaris 8,9,10 SPARC, AIX, LINUX, Along with all clusters&Vmware.

CERTIFICATIONS:

- > EMC Proven Professional, Associate Information Storage and Management, (EMCPA)
- > EMC Proven Professional, Implementation Engineer Symmetrix Solutions Specialist Version 6.0 (EMCIE)
- EMC Proven Professional, Implementation Engineer CLARiiON Solutions Specialist Version 5.0 (EMCIE)
- > EMC Proven Professional, Implementation Engineer Storage Area Network (SAN) Specialist Version 5.0 (EMCIE)
- > EMC Proven Professional, Implementation Engineer VPLEX Specialist Version 1.0 (EMCIE)

EMC Corporation *Client: Bankofamerica* Solutions Architect.

OCT 2012 - Till date

- Daily maintenance and administration of enterprise SAN that included several SymmetrixVmax3 arrays, DMX arrays and CLARiiON connected to several Windows & UNIX servers in the Data center.
- Virtual Pool Migrations from R6 to R1. Draining TDATs.
- Configuring and Managing Brocade and Cisco Switches using Brocade and CISCO CLI. Performing Zoning activities (using WWN). Creating aliases and Zones, adding zones to zoneset.
- Implemented Business Continuity Solution SRDF & configuring using Clone emulation on Symmetrix V-MAX3.
- Using EMC Grab and Heat reports Preparing the remediation reports and migration procedures.
- Migrating the data from old storage arrays to new EMC VMAX arrays using different migration technologies like Open Replicator ,Open Migrator/LM& SRDF.
- Migrating data by using different type of Host based copies like SVM, ASM, LVM.
- Provisioning storage from several VMAX, DMX-3, DMX-4,VNX5700, CX3-40, CX4-80 to Windows, Solaris, HP-UNIX and AIX servers.
- Migrated 6 IBM SVC to VMAX 20K (800 hosts) by using Image mode Migrating tool.
- Migrated 2 HITACHI arrays to VMAX 200K (200 hosts) by using Open Replicator.
- Migrated around 4000 hosts (project scope is 20, 000) from DMX, VMAX to VMAX200K and VMAX3
- Created scripts to automate the mapping and masking of LUNS using SYMCLI
- Decommissioning the servers from old array after migrating to new array.
- Installing the HBA drivers, firmware's, power path and patches on servers as part of remediation.
- Working in disaster recovery operations to perform the DR exercise to check the data consistency at the remote site using failover, update and failback operations.



EMC Corporation Global Residency Practice

• Troubleshooting routine critical issues including server throughput, port availability, zone requirements, PowerPath issues, host issues.

EMPLOYMENT

Software Solution Group inc

EMC Corporation Client: Bankofamerica

Sr. Storage Migration Specialist

June 2012 - OCT 2012

- Daily maintenance and administration of enterprise SAN that included several Symmetrix V-Max arrays, DMX arrays and CLARiiONs connected to several Windows & UNIX servers in the Data center.
- Configuring and Managing Brocade and Cisco Switches using Brocade and CISCO CLI. Performing Zoning activities (using WWN). Creating aliases and Zones, adding zones to zoneset.
- Implemented Business Continuity Solution SRDF & configuring using Clone emulation on Symmetrix V-MAX.
- Using EMC Grab and Heat reports Preparing the remediation reports and migration procedures.
- Migrating the data from old storage arrays to new EMC VMAX arrays using different migration technologies like Open Replicator and Open Migrator/LM.
- Migrating data by using different type of Host based copies like SVM, ASM, LVM.
- Provisioning storage from several VMAX, DMX-3, DMX-4, CX3-40, CX4-80 to Windows, Solaris, HP-UNIX and AIX
- Created scripts to automate the mapping and masking of LUNS using SYMCLI
- Decommissioning the servers from old array after migrating to new array.
- Installing the HBA drivers, firmwares, power path and patches on servers as part of remediation.
- Working in disaster recovery operations to perform the DR exercise to check the data consistency at the remote site using failover, update and failback operations.
- Troubleshooting routine critical issues including server throughput, port availability, zone requirements, PowerPath issues, host issues.

EMPLOYMENT Prosoft Technologies

EMC Corporation

Client: Bankofamerica

Sr. Storage Migration Specialist

June 2011 – June 2012

- Daily maintenance and administration of enterprise SAN that included several Symmetrix V-Max arrays, DMX arrays and CLARiiONs connected to several Windows & UNIX servers in the Data center.
- Configuring and Managing Brocade and Cisco Switches using Brocade and CISCO CLI. Performing Zoning activities (using WWN). Creating aliases and Zones, adding zones to zoneset.
- Implemented Business Continuity Solution SRDF & configuring using Clone emulation on Symmetrix V-MAX.
- Using EMC Grab and Heat reports Preparing the remediation reports and migration procedures.
- Migrating the data from old storage arrays to new EMC VMAX arrays using different migration technologies like Open Replicator and Open Migrator/LM.



EMC Corporation Global Residency Practice

- Migrating data by using different type of Host based copies like SVM, ASM, LVM.
- Provisioning storage from several VMAX, DMX-3, DMX-4, CX3-40, CX4-80 to Windows, Solaris, HP-UNIX and AIX servers.
- Created scripts to automate the mapping and masking of LUNS using SYMCLI
- Decommissioning the servers from old array after migrating to new array.
- Installing the HBA drivers, firmware's, power path and patches on servers as part of remediation.
- Working in disaster recovery operations to perform the DR exercise to check the data consistency at the remote site using failover, update and failback operations.
- Troubleshooting routine critical issues including server throughput, port availability, zone requirements, PowerPath issues, host issues.

EMPLOYMENT Prosoft Technologies

EMC Corporation

Client: Micron Technologies

Sr. Storage Architect

April 2011 - May 2011

- Performed necessary storage infrastructure maintenance in accordance with EMC and customer's change management policies.
- Created scripts to automate the mapping and masking of LUNS using SYMCLI
- Responsible for ongoing management of configuration and layout of storage infrastructure.
- Configured 400 TB of Disks in Brand New VMAX, and created Pool and adding DATA Devices.
- Configured &created Brand New POOLs and and Implemented Virtual Provisioning.
- Allocated 350 TB storage to Brand New HP 7000 Rack Clusters in 24 path.
- Day to day architectural needs for Microns Storage Requirement and implementations.
- Recognized gaps and provided best practices to the processes for zoning, masking and mapping.
- Provide architectural designs and suggest alternative methodologies and techniques for new projects and initiatives.
- Architected and implemented the necessary tools and procedures for monitoring storage devices.
- Established a standard storage report format based on the inputs from Storage Delivery Manager by utilizing StorageScope.
- Implemented ESRS IP Solution for Call Home

EMPLOYMENT Prosoft Technologies

EMC Corporation *Client: FreddieMac* Sr. Storage Admin

JAN 2011 - April 2011

- Performed environmental analysis by running Grabs on required Servers which are going to migrate to new storage(VMAX) and upload to HEAT. Submitted in understandable spreadsheet to system administrator team to perform server remediation including up-gradation of HBA firmware, device drivers, Power path versions, Vxvm, Vxfs, Vcs, SymCLI.
- Migrated SAN from Mc DATA 6064 to Brocade DCX as part of the data migration and created LSANs and Zones.
- Implemented virtual provisioning on V-MAX, DMX-4 by creating data devices, thin pools, thin devices using SYMCLI & SMC
- Implemented Auto provisioning on V-MAX by creating Masking View, Initiator Group ,Port Group, Storage Group using SYMCLI & SMC.



EMC Corporation Global Residency Practice

- Implemented Business Continuity Solution TimeFinder Mirror by configuring BCVs and using Clone emulation on Symmetrix V-MAX.
- Allocated storage to Solaris, AIX, HP-UX, Linux, ESX and windows servers from V-MAX and CX-4 storage arrays.
- Migrated data from DMX-3/DMX-4 to V-MAX using Open Replicator.
- Conducted VMAX and VNX Presentations.
- Facilitated the setup of SRDF link from DMX4 in Reston Datacenter to the VMAX at the Disaster Recovery site

EMPLOYMENT Prosoft Technologies

EMC Corporation

Client: Portland General Electric

Storage Admin

NOV 2010 - JAN 2011

- Performed environmental analysis by running Grabs on required servers which are going to migrate to new storage(VMAX) and upload to HEAT. Submitted in understandable spreadsheet to system administrator team to perform server remediation including up-gradation of HBA firmware, device drivers, Power path versions, ODM file set, Vxvm, Vxfs, Vcs, SymCLI.
- Performed knowledge transfer on array based Data migration using Open Replicator from DMX-4 to V-MAX and host based data migration software using Open Migration/LM
- Performed Knowledge transfer on new V-MAX features including Auto Provisioning, Virtual Provisioning along with masking views Naming convention to existing storage team.
- Migrated Boot SATA luns from DMX-4 to V-MAX.
- Good Knowledge on IBM Virtual I/O Servers (VIO) including LPARS.
- Good Knowledge on IBM virtualization technology LPAR which includes Clusters (AIX 6.1 OS).
- Good knowledge on Implementation of NPIV (Node Port Id Virtualization)
- Architect and implement new storage technologies and technics.

Prosoft Technologies June 2010- NOV 2010

- Installed and configured of hardware and OS on servers, workstations and I/O devices on SUN Fire and SPARC environment.
- System builds from the scratch for UNIX and Linux system.
- Responsible for NFS and Configured NFS Servers and Clients and troubleshooting system and NFS issues.
- Installed and configured new hard drives and memory.
- Package, Patches management, migration, integration & distribution in development, testing, QA, Training, Production environment.
- Used Admintool for adding and managing new users, groups, software and printers.
- Involved in disk configuration and disk crash recovery using format and fdisk. Created new slices, mounted new file systems and unmounted file systems.
- Created Korn shell scripts to automate Cron jobs and system maintenance. Scheduled Cron jobs for job automation.
- Involved in preparation of functional and system specifications. Estimated Storage requirements for applications.
- Installed of all the required Software, patches, documentation, licensing trouble shooting.
- Responsible for fax link and send mail.



EMC Corporation Global Residency Practice

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- > Trained on **Red Hat OpenStack Administration**
- > Reading Knowledge of **Big Data Administration**.
- > Trained on Amazon Web Services

EDUCATION:

Herguan University , Sunnyvale, CA. Masters in Computer Science

Graduated 2010

JNTU , Hyderabad, India Bachelor of Technology Graduated 2006